[music]
Welcome to North 100, a Canadian
Highlander podcast. My name is Serge.
Joining me today, I've got a Nelly.
>> Hey, I'm here.
>> I got a Wheeler
>> Fractured.
>> And on tech today, we've got a Paul.
>> Hello.
>> And welcome to the reality fracture set
review. A reminder that our set reviews
are not exhaustive. We do not talk about
every single card. We just talk about
the cards that we think are going to be
impactful for the format or we think
that you're going to ask questions
about. It's also predominantly the main
set today. We're only going to be
focusing on a small artisal hand
selection of the commander cards. So,
look forward to all that. But first, of
course, our sponsors. If you see any
cards today that you want to pick up,
consider buying them over at Card
Kingdom. Carding kingdom.com/lrr.
Let them know that we sent you. While
you're there, ask for a button. It'll be
very long, very wordy,
>> many words.
>> It'll it'll run off the screen. If
you've been watching our streams, you
know exactly the button I'm talking
about. If you want good cards, put them
in good sleeves over at Dragon Shield.
Use code LRMTG5 at checkout for 5% off.
And of course, everything that we do
here is brought to you by you with your
support over the Patreon.
patreon.com/loading
readyun reality fracture. You boys
stoked? And boy are my arms tired.
>> A mass Jace like you flew all the way
over here. Well then without further
ado, let's get into our very first card.
It's a Planaineswalker. It's a Johnny.
It's a Johnny Resolute. This is another
two mana planaineswalker. Fairly spooky
for one and a white. It enters play with
two loyalty. It has a static ability.
Whenever you gain life, put a loyalty
counter on a Johnny. Has an activated
ability for zero. Gain a life minus
four. create a two two um a Johnny's
Pride Mate basically. So, you know, it's
a two two and every time you gain a
life, put a plus one plus one counter on
it and you get an emblem for minus 10.
All creatures you control get plus two
plus two. And I can't think of anybody
more qualified to talk about wasting my
time uh than Wheeler on life gain.
Wheeler,
>> I'll waste everybody's time. Serge,
don't worry. Um, yeah. This is It's not
Renin six,
but it's not Tibultt the Phoenix.
>> I was gonna say this is the third ever
two mana planaineswalker. Is that is
that about right?
>> If there's one I'm forgetting, it must
be real terrible.
>> I mean, can you count MH3 Johnny?
>> Uh, I mean, I wish I didn't have to.
[laughter]
>> Am Nissa,
>> like Jace Vin's Prodigy or something,
right? Yeah. Yeah. Uh, this triggered
ability to put loyalty counters on a
john is pretty interesting, especially
uh because it's based off of how many
times you gain right or life rather than
uh how much life you're gaining.
>> So, being able to trigger this multiple
times with say a guide of souls and then
you play a raise the alarm or having a
Belladon took and then you cast a raise
the alarm.
um tokens. It It's kind of funny because
obviously if you're a deck that cares
about gaining life allow ruin your
evening uh or some versions of ruin your
evening I should say uh then this card
can get up to this ultimate or get up to
uh producing multiple a Johnny's
Pridemates. often if you're a deck that
can increase this card's loyalty when
you make an a Johnny's Pridemate that a
Pridemate is not going to be a 2 two
>> and it will actually just be like a
minus two instead of a minus4.
>> Um I'd be actually most interested
though in playing this in tokens.
>> Uh I've been dying to tokens a lot and
it's not just Jason Jobin. Um it's it's
just and a variety of different colors
and kind of sub builds as well. And life
gain is a sub build that kind of fits
pretty naturally into this. Like they
just happen to slap it on cards that
care about tokens. Anyway,
>> you got you got Celelesnia getting
Bright Glass Gear Hulk for uh Ocelot
Pride and Guide of Souls and then you
slot this beside it and you just cry,
right? [laughter]
>> Yeah. I mean, usually I try not to say
like, okay, so you take this broken
card, have it tutor two more broken
cards.
>> Yeah. We have the philosophy you don't
need medium cards to make your broken
cards better, but It's worth it does
make cats, [laughter] right? Like that's
that's not nothing for another broken
card, a Johnny Nodle Pariah. Um I I like
this kind of card, but I am willing to
also accept that it is fairly niche in
where it goes. Like again, tokens being
the most um competitively viable arc
type that would play something like
this. And even then, I don't think every
version of that deck is playing this
card.
>> One of the most famous misses in the
history of this podcast was me this
podcast was me saying that Renin 6 was
fine. and you're like, ah, it like its
abilities are whatever. I mean, it's two
mana. And then everyone else looking to
me like I'm out of my mind. I can't wait
to see if the same thing happens to
Wheeler on his Reed on a Johnny here.
>> I feel pretty safe with my evaluation of
this life game.
>> If you do push the envelope on a ruin
your evening deck, so now it's a bit
more fast, a bit more medium, a bit less
like full grind mode until they want to
concede. I recommend ruin your
afternoon. [laughter] And yes,
>> start early. I have also considered the
inevitable food variant that we'll get
and I recommend ruin your dinner.
[laughter]
All right, let's move on to our next
card, the Enlightened Confidant. This is
a two mana 2 one core cleric for one in
a white with lifelink at the beginning
of your end step. If you gained life
this turn, surveil one. If you put a
card with mana value less than or equal
to the amount of life you gained this
turn into your graveyard this way, put
that card into your hand.
Nelly
>> [laughter]
>> I've read this card like five times and
I'm still just taking it all in. Um,
yeah, I I like it a lot. You know,
obviously a little bit situational, not
not too much different from a Johnny
Resolute we just saw. You were going to
want to pair it with other ways to gain
life. This isn't just a straight color
shifted dark confident that's going to
gain you card advantage. But what it
does do is is really exciting. Um, you
know, I like that the one of the big
thrusts of the opposite dark confidant
here is that you want to hit your delve
cards, you know, instead of trying to
avoid them. Like you want to hit as many
uh as many uh mana values as you can so
that you gain more life, which is
exciting. Also, just like I don't know,
reminds me a lot of ocelot pride because
it goes to your endstep and checks if
you gained life and then if you did,
it's party time, you know. Um,
>> put this into your other decks. They're
already gaining life.
>> What do you mean by wanting to flip big
cards? Sorry.
>> Uh, if you put a card with man less than
or equal to the amount of life you gain
this way into your graveyard, put that
card into your hand.
>> Yeah. So, if you gain three life, but
you flip a nine drop, you don't get the
card that'sard.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, that's
>> I guess it's sort of like a balancing
act between it.
>> Yeah. No, you know what? I have read
this card more than once and I did the
magic player thing where I saw a mana
value and [laughter] was like, gain that
much more life for.
>> Oh, sure, sure, sure, sure, sure. Yeah.
It wasn't meant to be a call out on that
one. I'm like, did I read this card
wrong?
>> You're good. No, you're good. Uh, but
yeah, I mean, it does want you to gain
as much life as possible.
>> Yeah. I mean, there's no I mean, there's
very few chances to miss on this, too.
You just get You gained one life. You
gained zero life and you flip a land,
you just get to draw that card.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's important.
>> Well, I mean, I guess no, you have to
have gained one.
>> You have to gain one life. You have to
have gained one life for it to work,
which is which is the same as also
private. Like, you have to have gained
life. But even if you just get the
surveill one, that is also kind of okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But sometimes you're gonna put
cards in your hand as well.
>> I'm slamming this in D and D.
>> I don't know.
>> You don't like this?
>> I'm a little hesitant.
>> Yeah.
>> I just I just figure a low cost of
inclusion two drop cuz the deck is so
three drop heavy.
>> Yeah.
>> DNT. You look at me like I'm crazy when
I said the deck is so three drop heavy.
>> No, that's not the the part that I'm
wiggling eyebrows over.
>> Yeah. And I don't know. Just the ability
to gain some life.
>> No, you don't. But the
>> I'm going to try it. This man's being
extremely reserved because I want you to
know how much he loves two drops.
>> I mean, I'm going to play this card. I'm
just not expecting on playing this card
in a deck where like I'm going to say a
good deck, but mostly as a self-own,
right?
>> No, I I agree with that plan. I think
this deck is or this card is really
exciting in bad decks.
>> Yes. Yeah. Which I mean, you know,
[laughter]
that's not to pander to exactly our
audience, but Yeah.
So, when uh when Hobbit came out, there
was that mythic two drop that I don't
even remember her name that we're like,
"This card is very mid. It
>> Oh, you mean the Queen of Dale, the card
that has only had one appearance in the
Canadian Highlander Winners archive
since that went up and then the player
that uh put it in their deck took it out
immediately and did
>> so yeah, the Queen of Dale were like,
"This card does nothing." And and our
comment section was like, "You're out of
your mind." Like there were multiple
people who were in there who were saying
that we were bad and our card evaluation
was bad and you're like this does
nothing.
>> It's weird that a card that's templated
so much like Ethersworn cannon or uh not
canist the soldier sorry. Um,
>> Esper Sentinel.
>> Esper Sentinel card that's coded so much
like Esper Sentinel and has the same
kind of like
>> four player game, two player game, both
are good kind of situations is so much
worse than Hounder. Like it's I don't
know. It's weird that the Queen of Veil
isn't better.
>> This at least has a keyword.
>> It's not legendary.
>> I mean, if it was human, I'd be losing
my mind,
>> but yeah. I don't know.
>> I just don't think this does something
that that deck is looking to alleviate.
>> That's right. Right. Like imagine dude
that that deck needs card draw.
>> Imagine I'm a combo.
>> You can clamp it. But yeah, if if
>> you can clamp it.
>> Imagine I'm a combo deck and I'm against
death and taxes and I'm sweating like,
oh, what's their what's their two drop
going to play?
>> Thalia
even even Cathar commando scary. And
then it's this. I'm like, oh, so this
does nothing.
>> That's valid. That's valid. I think of
this as like in the in the 90th cards
inclusion, you know, after land. I I
think no. I I actually don't think it's
going to fit into any like really solid
tier one archetypes, but I think it's a
lot of fun and has a bunch of like
interesting broken
>> open. I'll play this in the worst green
white deck you've ever seen that will go
three in one, right? Like it's
>> that's where that's where I'm at with it
also. Like I don't think it's a card
that you necessarily are cuz it's the
same with Dark Confidant right now by
the way like or like four years ago or
something whatever it is. It's like
people don't really play Dark Confidant
anymore, but still has hilarious like
broken draws.
>> That's cuz like Delve got so good. But
yeah.
>> Well, Bob Bob shows up. At least Bob
gets you like a card every time. That's
the true, right? This doesn't the Why?
It's 2026. Why play a card that doesn't
always do the thing? That's like That is
the reality of Canadian Highlander. We
don't have to play sometimes cards. We
get to play all the time cards.
>> No. No. self-imposed these shackles
because we want to be on the worst green
white deck you've ever seen trying to go
through one.
>> Well, I mean, yeah. And then I show up
and it's accidentally a DOUBLE UP.
[laughter] I'M LIKE,
>> EVERY TIME I GO, IT'S A DOUBLE UP. YEAH.
>> All right, let's move on. Uh, next up,
we have the flickering hound. This is a
four mana, two two dog for three in a
white. Whenever you cast a creature
spell, exile up to one other target
creature you control, then return that
card to the battlefield under its
owner's control. Wheeler. So, I think
Displacer Kitten, which this is a direct
call out to a a three and a blue for a
two two. When you cast a non-creature
spell, you flicker uh a non-land
permanent you control and it just comes
back to play. Uh I think that the kitten
is one of the most underplayed cards in
our format. This thing is busted. Like
if you play this card in Vintage Cube or
Vintage or Legacy, uh this card is
busted. And uh often this card, while
this card can be flickering powerful
artifacts like portal defraia or coveted
jewel or even just manava, um you can
also just flicker pretty powerful
creatures, initiative creatures, eternal
witness, spellseeker, uh all these
different cards. And flickering hound
more or less just does that. It does a
similar function to Displacer Kitten in
that you can be flickering, Eternal
Witness, Initiative Creatures, Spell
Seekers, Bright Glass, Gear Hulks, all
these cards uh that often see play in
say Bant Blink.
>> Yep. Um it's a card that also just
doesn't require you to have non-creature
spells where like if you're playing a
Bamplink deck, you have a bunch of
non-creature spells, but the often the
ones you play are uh going to do the
displacer kitten thing. So it's like a
hat on a hat. Whereas this is going to
make like Bamblink you'll have like
seven cards in hand and three of them
are Abison's Pilgrim. And so being able
to turn every Abisonson's Pilgrim into
Flickering
>> like another fee rate or something like
that.
>> Yeah. And I mean not to be too much of a
boomer but this is also the kind of card
where I look at this and I go like well
this is going to be broken with like
cloud fairies and like paragrin drake
and these like untapping creatures.
Um,
>> does this do something in um food chain?
>> Uh, probably. Yeah, like it it this is a
creature combo card
>> that can also just find a home in some
of the more grindy mid-range like B
blink initiative style decks.
>> Uh, really excited to mess around with
this card. It doesn't matter. It's a
four mana tutu. We It dies whatever like
they they die. I think yeah it's like
we've already learned that displacer
kitten is like the line where you're
like
>> it's okay that this is a four mana 2 two
like we like [laughter] that card showed
us that whereas like it hasn't seen a
ton of playing Canadian highlander but
like you know the same players have
played vintage cube and like
>> I don't know people people have been
I've I've put it in decks like I know
I've seen it out there in the wild just
not as I agree it's I think it's
underplayed still
>> it it's a classic like you kind of need
the defense grid but when you have or
like a silence or whatever they are They
tap out, but when they do, they lose.
>> This is Yeah, this is the the like the
turbo button. You're like, we're close
and then now it's over.
>> Notably, this can't flicker itself.
Displacer kitten can save itself. Uh,
but if we're playing this in blink,
>> you got the safe button,
>> then you probably have some cards to
save this card. Even if it even if it
had shroud.
>> Yeah,
>> I would still or or like some reverse
hex proof or something. Even had some
drawback that prevented that. I would
still argue to put this in your blink
deck because it's so wild that you can
cook with just cast creature spell
instead of needing a non-creature spell
to get it going.
>> Um and also I need to say that like as
as a boomer, right, we've strayed so far
from restoration angels light like this
used the ability to
>> I was just thinking that man. Yeah.
>> Yeah. like the ability to flicker more
than one time, like recursively as often
as you can pay the,
>> you know, very minimal cost of having
creatures in your 50 creature blink
deck. Like,
>> this used to cost a lot more mana to get
this kind of power.
>> There was uh that one bird in Bloomberg
that had something similar.
>> Oh, the the swan.
>> Yeah. Every time you cast another bird,
you can flicker. You're like, it was
very niche.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Anyways,
>> uh moving on, we've got Gideon's
Memorial. Two mana legendary artifact
for one and white creature tokens you
control. Get plus one plus zero and have
vigilance.
It's a mana rock. Tap to add one mana of
any color. Spend this only to cast
planaineswalker spells. And you can also
pay one and a white and discard this
card to deal four damage to target
attacking or blocking creature. Have fun
with this modal card, Nelly.
>> It's okay. I heard from Wheeler recently
that tokens are under control and not a
problem at all. It's the only It's quite
literally the only thing that I've been
like dropping matches to the past six
months.
>> It's a powerful archetype. Yeah, I It
makes sense that like um a strategy that
revolves around getting a little bit
more than one card out of every card in
your deck works well in a format that's
like accelerated to the point that
playing sweepers wrong. We you also have
said in the past 12 months is like I
think just play Talisman into Wrath of
God is a viable strategy right now.
That's too good. If you can turn, wrath
of God, Tfairy or Elspath, shake my
hand.
>> And [laughter] your is your Does your
first turn have to be Thought Sees, or
is it just tap land?
>> N tap.
>> Tap land.
>> Irrigated farmland.
>> With everybody with everybody developing
to the board so aggressively, the
creatures being so pushed, I think
wrath's at an all-time premium, right?
Anyways,
>> toxic deluge. Um, yeah,
>> you're losing a combo if you're on blue
white anyways, you might as well just
like sweep the oppose the creatures.
Exactly.
>> Yeah. So, like this is kind of nuts.
Those many of those token decks were
already playing the the same thing for
Ministrod that also gives you a
toughness that I've cast so few times in
my life. I don't remember the name.
>> Well, they banded [laughter] intangible
virtue.
>> They did banded in block, right? Yeah.
Anyways, second intangible virtue is
pretty cool. It's an artifact that might
matter possibly.
>> I don't know that it'll matter. It's
pretty cool next to Robots, though.
There's four different lines of text on
this card. And I feel like if you care
about two of them, it's good enough to
play it, right? Like it's another
Agonjo. It's another intangible virtue.
It's another two mana legendary rock,
right? Like and it cares about planes
walkers as well.
>> The the worst part about this card is
that it's also just a free manaixing or
color fixing mana rock for only planes
walkers.
>> But like tokens is also one of the arc
types that is still casters.
play else
like blue white palcatraz you're like oh
I actually love I love all of these
modes like the the token part's not that
relevant but my planaines walkers make
tokens but I'll take a rock that casts
my things I'll take another copy of a
ganjo right like this with academy runes
[laughter]
>> right yeah this card's cool this card's
very cool
>> yeah looks very scary uh definitely goes
in tokens decks not really any other
places but it's going to be annoying
that the tokens deck have this
>> yep
All right, next up we have Guiding
Hydra. This is X and a white for a hydra
horror. It's a 1 zero, but this creature
enters with X plus1 plus1 counters on
it. At the beginning of combat on your
turn, you may remove a plus one plus1
counter from this creature. If you do,
put a plus one plus one counter on each
other creature you control. Wheeler,
>> welcome back, Big Mike. The real ones,
they think the mono black mayas is the
big mic. Uh-uh. No, no, no. That's
medium.
>> No. Meas the lunar. That X that that X
is like six. You're tapping a Gas Cradle
or something. Uh this is a one drop, so
you can find it off of your Gearhulk,
your Ranger Revios, your uh Ranger
captain, uh all that stuff. Um I like
this card in decks that really want to
find the one drops. uh decks that might
play Starfield.
>> Starfield Shepherd. Starfield Shepherd.
>> Yeah,
>> DNT Tech right there.
>> It's just nice to have a one drop that
uh can grow your board uh very quickly.
Um it's really annoying this card. It's
It's kind of funny. It doesn't feel like
a 2026 Magic card on I mean the rate
does, but it's just there's so few words
on it. Uh [laughter]
>> yeah, there's no keywords.
>> We've also talked about how Mono White
just has so many cards that care about
counters. Yep.
>> And uh while you shouldn't go you I mean
if you want to go all in on hardened
scales in your Mono White deck, sure go
off, but like you don't need to. It's
just another card that can maybe say
like, "Hey, you have like the Matt
Murdoch from Marvel jumpst start or
whatever that says all your things with
counters have ward."
>> Uh then great. This card can do
something in a in a version of DT with
that.
>> Yeah. Agent Smith puts a counter on this
guiding hydra spreads it out after.
>> Yeah, like gets uh card. I mean, it's a
creature, so it's good with a robaroid,
but it's [laughter]
>> it's particularly good with a robberoid,
though.
>> Easy to tutor, grows your team, gives
you a mana sync, and um even if you just
play this like in tokens, not to bring
up tokens again, but we're in white. Uh,
even if you just play this as like a I'm
going to buff my team uh twice over like
two turns and just have a creature,
that's not that bad.
>> Yeah, honestly, like Big Mike and
Tokens, I don't know. I'm not sure how
long it's been since Big Mike has been
like a viable option. I just know that
Big Mike and tokens is still a thing in
cube. And so, every time I've done it in
the past like five years or whatever,
like going back, like this is only once
or twice, but it's still just like at
modern cube rates, it still just feels
like this is okay. I wish it did it a
turn faster. That's actually still okay.
>> I definitely played Big Mike in uh Mono
White when Ranger Captain of EOS got
printed in uh yeah for Modern Horizons
and uh Manac Crypt was underpointed like
it was great in that era.
>> There was there was
>> and you know the play patterns of these
cards are very strong. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So yeah, we're just calling
Guiding Hydra essentially MC the Lunar
with haste. Yeah, that also depends
because you don't need a tap for its
ability. Yeah. I wish it went down a
turn earlier like you just said. Yeah.
>> All right. Next up, we have Liliana, the
Faultless.
>> Another one drop. One mana, one one
legendary human cleric. She's been color
shifted. Whenever another creature or
plains walker you control enters gain a
life, one tap and discard a card,
another target creature or
planaineswalker you control gains
hexroof until end of turn. Nelly. Well,
kids, back in my day, we had to play
Guide to Souls as one card and Soul and
Mom as another. Um, yeah. I don't know.
This is another pretty cool one drop. I
think it like
you're going to have to tell me. You're
going to have to tell me if this is
going to stay the course and make it all
the way into DNT, but I definitely think
in the like piles of Soul Wardens decks,
you're going to want to consider this.
Sure, it's legendary, but we tend not to
worry about that too much for one drops.
Um, you know, it gaining life on
planaineswalkers. Maybe that matters at
some point.
>> So, I'm probably not playing this in D
and D. Like, I'm not on scroll, for
example. Like, I'm on I'm on Mum and I'm
on Stepmom, but I'm not going that deep
on multiple other versions of that
protection.
>> That's totally fair. The the costing a
card is not nothing, but the flexibility
of also gaining a life is like kind of
impressive. You want to try?
>> Maybe you should. I should be on strike.
I think the best thing that Death and
Taxes can do right now is play a one
drop that protects your two drop that
says your opponent can't play magic.
>> Valid valid. Now, this isn't good at
that either.
>> No, unfortunately. [laughter]
>> Yeah. We drew an ancient.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, but it's you still just
play her. You play maximum number of
moms, you know, in that strategy that
Wheeler's talking about. And so, anytime
you're playing max moms, you probably
play
>> Liliana.
Who their mom maxing right now?
>> Right. How [laughter] many moms are in
your phone book? Yeah. Uh,
>> buddy, I've been mom maxing.
>> Yeah, I'm eating the cookies. No, I
don't know there. I'm not sure what else
to say about this card. It's like it
does both these things. That's weird.
>> It's a one mana card with so much deck.
>> It only costs one mana. Like, it's still
not like probably as high up in the
hierarchy as Rag of Honor or Ocelot
Bride, but it came from a standard set.
Like, this card's pretty messed up. All
right, next up, we have the Loyal Tutor.
One mana instant for single white pip.
Search your library for a
Planaineswalker card. Reveal it,
shuffle, and put that card on top.
Wheeler,
>> this is so funny. Did you Did any of us
actually think that we'd get a new one
mana instant speed? Put a card on top of
your deck tutor.
>> No. Are we going to get the one that
puts a land out? Like, how many card
types are we?
>> Maybe. You know what? Maybe I would have
said yes for like the worst battle.
>> Yeah, battles. Yeah. [laughter] Yeah.
One minute for that one should be one
mana instant. and put it in your hand.
It'd be fine.
>> Yeah, that would be fine. In fact, it
should
pay for itself. Yeah.
>> Uh the I I think this card is probably
not going to be widespread. Um I'm a
little hesitant to even include it in
decks that care about Planaines Walkers.
Uh there aren't a ton of them anymore
running around. You know, we have the
the Palcatraz or the Super Friends decks
that do pop up and uh they're they're
not bad. escape shift turns as well.
Tends to there are versions that play a
bunch of
>> planes walkers.
>> Really, really, really want three fairy
every single game.
>> I do. And actually, that's the one one
of the planes walkers I'll shout out is
to fairy time traveler because not only
is that a card that is very powerful
across a variety of arc types and can in
fact even just kind of shut down some of
them, um, but it is a planaineswalker
that can combo, right? I you I feel like
you kind of need a little bit of both.
Like Worldly Tutor is really well I
don't want to say Worldly Tutor is
really good, but Worldly Tutor is good
because it can find uh combo creatures
and like a metamorphosis fanatic and
like a collector roof, right?
>> Reasons to play a tutor for it.
>> Yeah. You you get the the options uh to
choose from.
>> It's a toolbox. It gets you multiple
hits,
>> right? And so, but I really think you
need that ability to just like pop your
opponent if you fire this off with the
right configuration of cards. And you
get that with a couple of Planaines
Walkers, but some of them are pretty
bad. Uh, to very three is at least quite
good, but like I don't know. It's uh
>> could big Boros play this card.
>> I was at one point kind of had a toolbox
spread of Planes Walkers.
>> Yeah. The one other deck that I think
might work for it is like Esper low to
the ground artifact matters decks. like
being able to get a Ka Planaineswalker
like the three mana Ka cuz like that
loyal tutor can then tutor for
artifacts. You can get three mana
tesarate or
>> what did I say? Three mana card.
>> I meant sorry. Yeah, three mana
tesarate. You can get one of the four
mana tesarate,
>> five mana tesarate.
>> I [laughter] mean I I guess that it is
worth mentioning that if uh I'm not
telling you to play this in storm, but
the fact that this one mana card can
find uh which can lock somebody out or
be the protection piece or this is one
mana for a three mana black lotus.
>> It's all nothing, [laughter] right?
>> Yeah. Loyal Tutor into Tesarate into
Lotus into Yeah,
>> I don't think we're going to see a lot
of this card.
>> I'm going to be a bit more blunt and
just tell you not to play this card
every if you're looking at this card and
getting excited about it. Please don't
buy one off the off the pre-order.
Please unless you go to card
kingdom.com/hiller then in which case
buy four.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Uh next up we have repurposed
enforcer. This is a two mana 32 human
soldier for one in a white. It has no
face. Whenever this creature attacks,
empower Jace X, where X is the number of
creatures that you control. Uh, this set
is actually very new mechanic light. One
of the big big and only mechanics in the
new set is actually the new empower
Jace. Uh, to empower Jace, you make a
Jace token if you don't already control
one. You make a Jace token and you put X
loyalty counters on it. By default, the
Jace Plains Walker has minus one
surveill one minus three draw card. Um,
if you already control a Jace Plains
Walker, you just iterate up the one that
you have.
>> If you already control a Jace Plains
Walker token token token Yeah, you can't
put those counters on another Jace.
Thank you. But you can put them on the
token of cunning Castaway.
>> Sure.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, Nelly.
>> Okay. So, pretty weird little uh 32 for
for two. Um, there's some utility here.
Obviously, like DNT maybe enjoys like a
human that draws them cards when it
attacks.
I think you could consider playing it in
tokens as well where you're going to
have a wide number of creatures you
control. But overall, I think this card
is pretty flavor of the week. Like, uh,
yeah, go to the pre-release, get
yourself a Jace token card to put in
with any of the empower Jace cards that
you find from the set that you want to
try out. This one I I'm not I'm not
seeing the longevity.
>> It's so weird.
>> It's a weird card. It it rewards you for
having a lot of creatures that are
attacking and then, you know, gives you
a card extra every turn if you're able
to hit three creatures attacking while
this thing survives. But, you know, the
two drop that I want to play in DNT that
cares about a lot of creatures is the
the kinser.
>> Yeah. Kinser sentry or whatever it's
called. It's just like,
>> yeah, it's a two two and when it
attacks, you get to put uh a creature
into play with mana value less than or
equal to the number of creatures that
are attacking. That's a first dragon
lifelink,
>> right? And it's like you don't tell me
you're going to cut your Sunold Sentinel
that's keeping their like Barrogoy from
popping off for this thing, you know?
It's not it's it's neat. This card's
neat,
>> you know? We we use this kind of this
line a lot where it's like imagine if
you showed a Nadu to a Magic player in
2010. They'd explode or whatever. And
it's like I don't know, people in that
era like we know what broken cards were.
We've seen them. This is the kind of
card where if I showed this to someone
in 2010, they'd be like, "What the hell
are you talking about?"
>> Were there any planes walkers in 2010?
>> There were, but like
>> make a Jace Tob
Jace X. I don't know, man.
>> Why is it a two mana 3 two?
>> Do Magic cards still have faces in 2026?
You know, like
>> Yeah. Uh, it's a weird card, but hey, if
you play it and attack with it, you will
then draw a card. You may draw a card.
Like, it's not terrible.
>> All right, our final white card is going
to be Teao, Light Shield Expert. Two
mana, one legendary creature, human
cleric for one and a white. It has
flash. When Teao enters, return target
permanent.
>> Nope.
>> When Teao enters, target permanent you
control gains hexroof until end of turn.
Put a plus one plus1 counter on it if
it's a creature. put a loyalty counter
on it if it's a Planaineswalker Wheeler.
>> I'm a big fan of this card. Um, it's a
two mana flash legend with an ETB that
doesn't really care if it gets Caracus.
In fact, you might be the one doing the
Caracus.
>> Uh, target permanent is huge. Being able
to protect everything like protecting
your lands from your opponents like
Wasteland or Strip is so sick.
>> Um, obviously protecting your creatures
is quite good. Uh the fact that you
could just use this as a combat trick to
like buff your creature and push damage.
Um you can pro like it always adds an
additional counter as well. So there
are, you know, proactive plays you can
make of like, let's say you are playing
this in a deck with a planaineswalker
and they're like, "Okay, well, next turn
I'll just kill their planaineswalker
before it ultimates." And then you play
this and advance your planaineswalker
and then you get an ultimate or
something or it, you know, pushes it
above a certain threshold where they
can't kill it. Um, I I'll try this out
in versions of of Death and Taxes
because again, I I put a pretty high
emphasis or or strong emphasis on
protecting your broken cards that
prevent your opponent from playing the
game.
>> Um, might be interested in I think Angel
might try this in Esper Flash. Um, it
does have flash and it's [laughter] in
the it has flash. It's in the Esper
colors and that for what it's worth that
is a deck that has the similar mindset
of like here's an opposition agent. you
will not be able to kill it. Or here's a
spell queller. You will not be able to
kill it.
>> No, between like this and night nurse,
like a lot of very interesting two drops
that you can put in.
>> Yeah, they're really annoying, man. Like
two man holding open two white mana is
so annoying now. It's like am I getting
reprieved or am I getting like
completely blown out, you know?
>> I like it a lot in the um Nile Legends
deck as well. That one's It's sort of
the inverse of the DNT philosophy where
it's just like I have a creature that
puts two plus one plus one counters on
my creatures every turn. So if I just
keep that alive, then I get to attack
for 10. You know, it's like you you can
still play magic. I'm just going to try
and make sure you only play a magic for
one more turn.
>> Yeah. You don't get much.
>> So having this to just like keep your
most important creature alive seems
great. All right, next up we have um one
of the first cards that was spoiled.
This is Chandra Chill of Compliance.
Three mana blue Chandra Planaineswalker
for one blue blue enters with three
loyalty. It has four loyalty abilities
plus one surveil one if you put a
non-creature non-land card in your
graveyard this way. Put that card into
your hand. Plus one add a blue mana to
your mana pool. Spend this mana only to
cast a non-creature spell. Minus X. Tap
target artifact or creature and put X
stun counters on it. And minus six. You
get an emblem with whenever you cast a
spell, draw a card. Nelly,
>> it's a lot of words. It's a three mana
planaineswalker starts with three
loyalty. There's some good things going
on here. And I feel like this is the
kind of card that if you showed 2014
Sorenson or Blue White Hard Control,
they would be like, "What? Two frost
breaths for the price of one Frost
Breath?" Um because like that to me the
minus X is kind of the most exciting
part about this card where you can come
down minus X play pattern minus two and
then that there's two stun counters on
two creatures you just tapped.
>> No, no, put on it.
>> You can tap one turn for two turns, not
two.
>> They're making so many words on these
cards. I can't fit them all into my
heart. No, you're there. Yeah.
>> Oh, thank you. I appreciate God. Twice
this morning and like this is the first
card they spoil.
>> We'll give you one per color,
>> right? I agree. [laughter] That's what I
need clearly. Okay. All right. All
right. All right. So, you still you can
just tap a creature and put one or two
stun counters on it.
>> Can you pay zero
>> to tap a creature? Put zero. I don't
think you can pay zero.
>> No, I think there's a rule about
loyalty, but we have to pay at least.
>> There are some that are what? No, you
can pay zero. You can you can teaser it
for zero.
>> Okay, so you can just use it to
aggressively taper and not not put or
remove. Okay, that's neat. Anyways, I
just want to say, okay, even though I
thought you could tap two creatures with
it,
>> sure,
>> I still think this is a card that says
like, hey, I could get played in like
old next level blue or blue control,
they both kind of like me because
there's like the mana thing going on and
the messing with the board that the
tempo decks might have enjoyed back
then. And there's the three mana
planaineswalker build card advantage
thing that the hard control decks would
like. I don't know where the I don't
think Jess is playing this. Go ahead.
>> Scapeshift.
I've been dying for a three mana
planaineswalker that draws cards without
reducing its loyalty in some way, shape,
or form.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, Nars Parter of Veils kind of fell
off for me cuz you only get so many hits
even though obviously it bricks your
opponents. Uh, Dak Faden obviously
doesn't put you up cards. This can like
pass the turn with four loyalty and I
can be up cards or I can sculpt and make
sure I'm not hitting something that I I
don't want to cast, right? Um, being
able to also just play this on turn
three, untap, uh, tick up, cast a time
walk is pretty sexy. Um,
>> go to the five.
>> You know, you know what's the saddest
part about this card?
>> It loves Sensei's Divining Top cuz you
can just tap to draw with the top and
now there's a nonland non-creature card
on top of your library.
>> Okay, I might do that now. [laughter]
Yeah, that that might that might be that
might be hidden. I I totally agree with
that estimation like cuz because it it
is like a juicy card that has a bunch of
things going for it and so yeah if it
ends up with one or two ohms that's
great. I don't know.
>> Yeah,
>> this card doesn't offend me.
>> Yeah, it's it is a three mana blue
planaineswalker that can draw you cards
accelerate you keep you alive and has
four abilities like that emblem. If you
ever if you've ever played Shandra
Torture Defiance you'll know that that
card ultimates more than you'd expect.
>> Yeah. Getting to six. Not was this an
old Tamo alt as well? Something like
that. the that emblem.
>> The first one, the five mana one or
which Tamio?
>> Oh, no, that was tap an island draw
card. I think I'm conflating.
>> That's Muan Ling.
>> Muan Ling Tamo was
>> also a three mana plan walker that got a
lot of playing Canadian calendar
actually.
>> Yes. So,
>> yeah.
>> Um, yeah, I I'm excited for this card.
>> As a fellow escape shift enjoyer, I
might try it out. But I do want to put
my hand up and say, "Hey, Scape Shift
has those creatures that destroy you a
card every turn. You can play those
instead." Oh, I I think the I've been
playing so much scape shift and I think
if you just cut as many creatures as you
can.
>> Yeah, that's the that's the name of the
game instead of
>> push their fatal pushes. There is a
creature there's actually two creatures
that I want to play in scape shift in
the set.
>> There's at least one that you
>> Yeah, cut your quantum Riddlers and your
ameritus or whatever and just play cards
like this.
>> All right, next up we have Fibble.
Impossibly lost. Two mana 1-1 one
legendary Humunulous for one and a blue.
When one or more of your opponents are
dealt combat damage during your turn,
draw two cards. If your library has no
cards in it, you win the game. Fibble's
owner shuffles him into their library.
Wheeler,
>> I will try to play this card in a
Thasa's Oracle deck.
>> Hell yeah. Um, it's I I don't know how
often you're playing this card as a just
a two mana draw to. I think that's kind
of a losing sort of uh position.
Although it is kind of funny to hit
someone, this trigger goes on the stack
and you caracus it and you still draw
the cards and you replay it. But like I
this card can steal games with tainted
packed and with demonic consultation.
Um, which is so funny.
>> Yeah. You're more mid-range in this,
like you're playing creatures. You just
have a Thoracal package. Cuz I'm trying
to imagine a world in which you have
this in play and a way to deal damage
and a way to empty your library.
>> Well, this is the way you deal damage.
>> Yeah, you actually just cast this, wait
a turn, and then play one of the like I
think there's three one blue mana
cantrips that make a creature
unblockable and draw a card.
>> You could do that. I I'm just going to
fatal push their creature and hit them.
>> All right. Like I think I don't I I
don't think you need to use too many
tools to get the party started, but like
I want to take advantage of the you win
the game text. And like if I'm playing
Thoracle,
are you like I'm playing Thoral and
we're going into game two, are you
keeping hands with like Galvanic
Discharge and stuff?
>> Sure. Right.
>> If you have to.
>> If you have to. But but people panic.
They mug in way too aggressively. You
hand attack their stuff if they got it
to push this through. It's people in
this room mulligan way too aggressively.
>> Oh, this guy does.
>> Oh, okay. This guy does not.
>> I m I maul too aggressively.
>> I think you maul too aggressively.
>> Wow. Okay. Well, that's exciting.
>> Well, some actually, you know what
achievement. That's like No, that's
great. Yeah. Yeah. That's really proud.
>> I I think uh I mean we don't have to
turn this into another different
podcast. I I think Serge, you're a man
of extremes where like Oh, right.
>> Yeah. But uh
>> we're learning. We'll get there
eventually, right? With the correction.
This card's got to be the most fun card
in the set because like I agree with
you. I think people should try it. I
think you could slot it into ninjas.
>> Yeah,
>> cuz it's just like it's two mana, but
then it says like, "Hey, you play this
on your ninja turn now you're also
drawing two cards." I don't know.
>> It's funny like
>> and it's kind of annoying. Your opponent
has to read it. They're like, "It says
you win the game on here. What are you
up to?" and maybe they kill it and
you're like, "Yes,
>> I'm willing to take the shot to do the
cuz like again if even if I'm not
winning the game with this, if I'm able
to hit them, I'm drawing two cards.
That's pretty good."
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Next up, Gist of St. Thalia.
Two mana one two legendary spirit cleric
for one in a blue. Has flying and
non-creature spells you cast one less to
cast. [gasps]
Well, this card's so exciting and our
format just doesn't play Goblin
Electromancers
like you can you can do this in
Boomertorm if you want. You can
absolutely play uh cost reducers and we
used to a little bit like uh like the
first list I copied from I want to say
Aaron Patton might have been Robin
Sorenson
>> had
Robin used to always play uh Sphere of
awakening or something which one of the
two in fact just every spell cost
>> helm of awakening.
>> Helm of awakening. Yeah. for that's it's
a symmetrical everyone's spells of of
every genre cost one less to cast like
the first cost reduction card or
something from way back in the day in
the '90s. Thank you. Helm of Awakening
>> uh shown here in a Dominaria reprint.
But yeah, I I've I've long enjoyed the
idea of playing storm decks with cost
reducers like Goblin Archmancer or um
there's the one that cared about um
counter spells. There's the legendary
one three.
>> Brawl.
>> Brawl. Yeah, Brawl got some play.
>> You were speaking Surge.
>> No worries. No worries. Brawl had seen
some play in blue moon for a while in
our archetype because of the counter
spell thing. I think most
>> the reduction in the counter spell.
>> The second ability on Brawl did matter.
This is a Stormcrow. Um, which honestly
for a two mana cost reducer is fine.
Like I played Ethereum Sculptor for a
while and then just eventually looked at
other people's academy list like no one
else is doing this. And like it's kind
of a weird weak weak link in the deck
because these decks often as Wheeler was
just saying earlier about the team or
scape shift list. It's like you don't
really want to play stuff that makes
their removal live. So it's really hard
to fit cost reducers into our format.
And I think guys Saint Ali is a great
card. Like I think it's very cool.
>> Notably this one is noncreature whereas
a lot of them have been incense and
sorceries.
>> So you can cast artifacts for free
>> uh and your instance and sorceries which
is pretty appealing. We do have about
nine of these at two mana now. That's
insane.
>> I know there's tons, but I still don't
know if we can take advantage of it.
Enter the infinite for three.
>> This is the kind of card that you would
love to have on board while you're
piloting eggs, but never want to put in
your eggs deck.
>> I don't want to play the Yeah, I think
you need to play this in a deck with
like rituals or I had this deck that
technically won a tournament. Uh it was
like a rug heart
>> doing a lot of work there. Well, it won
a Thursday lander, but there was like 20
people. Uh, it's it was a rug heartbeat
of spring.
>> Sure.
>> Turns combo deck.
>> Oh,
>> where you like you you played a bunch of
time walks and and whatnot. Um, and you
played all these cost reducers to
basically try and get around the fact
that the heartbeat and mana flare cards,
both three mana enchantments that double
each player's mana, are symmetrical,
trying to break that symmetry. and the
fact that these cards just die like
right if you un if you pass a turn with
one of these they're probably going to
kill them. Yeah. Um
>> so we have a I I'd be curious to revisit
that deck cuz now we have a density of
these kind of cards and we also just
have a bunch of busted cantrips that we
can now reduce the cost of right like
we're not playing this and then casting
chartic course. We're casting flow state
and stock up and for
>> right like that's exciting. I'm not
saying that this is the best thing to
do, but I I think this card and this
type of card maybe has a little more
play if you just go you can't kill them
all.
>> Sure. Okay. All right. So, we're
noticing a high water mark in terms of
these like two mana cost reducers.
Wheeler thinks maybe some weird garbage
platter deck that he had cooking before.
Would love to see these. So, I'm I'm
excited for the future of guys of Saint
Thalia. By the way, what did you call
that deck? Cuz it sounds like you could
port monto garbage platter and groundhog
day.
>> I think it was just I think I just
called it heartbeat turns. Although I
did have Big Gay Electric Prince
Moonstorm.
>> Okay.
>> Which was like that but in blue red with
moons as a way to be like you can't kill
my goblin electro man if you don't have
black mana there. White mana. Yeah.
Nice.
>> And then they bolt it. You're like
>> all right. Next up, Jace Reality
Sculptor. Five mana. Jace enters with
five loyalty plus one empower Jace X
where X is the number of islands you
control. Minus three until your next
turn. Whenever a creature attacks you or
a planaineswalk you control gets minus 5
minus zero until end of turn and zero.
Exile all but the bottom card of each
opponent's library. Activate only if
there are 25 or more loyalty counters
amongst Jes.
Wheeler.
>> This card is so stupid. I don't think
it's particularly good, but every like
people are excited about this type of
card or about this card because it's
very funny
>> and people love alternate windcons.
>> They love all wind cons. Uh
unfortunately, Fibble costs two mana
whereas this cost five mana.
>> This card is outgunned by a fib.
>> Yeah, I my tune on planaineswalkers has
slightly been changing. I think these
Palcatraz lists are really important for
not not just like because they're fun
and cool, but because the format was
kind of lacking some prison elements
outside of like land destruction decks,
um, which can get out from under that
just by moxen and aggressive creatures
and and whatever. Um, and so I'm kind of
going through a re-evaluation of
Planaines walkers right now. And this
ain't it, Chief. This this is I don't
think this is it. That minus three is
appealing. Um, but the number like
number of islands five mana like is that
minus three though? Like sorry my I've
obviously been having a time reading
cards today and this is a weird ability
but minus three until your next turn.
Whenever a creature attacks you or
planes it gets minus five power until
end of turn. So it comes down with five
and then you can do that once. So it's
kind of like is that it's a five mana
fog. If you're if you're on the back
foot, you spend five mana for your fog
and now you have to empower Jason, draw
a card, and try to do something else and
then maybe both lose both your planes
walkers, right?
>> Yeah, we talked about old Tamo. I rather
play old Tamo
>> like first five mana Tamo from Sword.
>> I unironically love that card.
>> It's not that bad.
>> It's still like the It still has
powerful things on it.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh yeah, this card's funny.
>> Next up, Perfected Theory. This is a one
mana instant. It's modal. Choose one.
Target creature has base power and
toughness 1 one until end turn or target
creature has base power and toughness
four five Nelly. I'm like confused like
this ability for a long time cost three
and it let you draw a card. But now
they're like it's fine just print it at
one mana.
>> I love monol blue giant growth.
>> Seriously though like you could put this
I don't know like if you slam this on an
infect creature.
>> In fact this is my brain goes mean this
is like a what was the snake form?
There's a green card. Target creature
gets veil pardon me from
>> Oh, you mean actual snake form.
>> Actual snake form there. No, there's a
one mana green spell that target
creature became like a 66 or something.
>> Scale up. Scale up. This is like blue
scale up.
>> Blue scale up.
>> Thank you.
[laughter]
>> Snake form is a card that Nelson and I
have played in Canadian Highlander, but
it has been about 17.
>> All right, guys. Welcome to a brand new
game of what card is Serge describing?
Yeah. Anyways, you keep
>> Yeah, it's blue giant growth. I don't
know. Scale up obviously does two more
power. Uh but is a sorcery and this one,
right?
>> Yeah. And but this one also can make
their creature a one-1 then kill it in
combat.
>> Yeah, dog. It's pretty cool.
>> It's a pretty cool card. It is in fact a
sorcery. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Cuz you you start your infect turn
with scale up and then see if they kill
your creature and then you're like, are
you dead?
>> Yeah.
>> I'm curious as to why we're going to
infect instead of just like blue red.
Like we could
>> Do you like this? Do you like this in
like blue black tempo as well? It's kind
of spicy.
>> Once again, I'd like to just go back to
blue red.
>> I want to target like I don't know,
monastery swifts here, a prowess
creature.
>> Uh I want to like target their barog so
my red burn spells can kill it.
>> This could be next to two other spells
that you cast on turn three that are
also both instance. The last of which
being berserk and you killed them
because they didn't block your one two
attacking monastery swift spirit. You
could. Yeah, you can do the berserk
stuff with this card, but I I really
just want to like
>> protect my creature or kill their kill
them. Like I just think that the
>> it's a it's one mana. It's a one mana
blue card that saves your creature or
kills your opponent.
>> Hey, nice merit lodge, idiot.
>> Yeah, and [laughter] I Oh, sorry. That's
the other thing I've died to. I've only
died [laughter] in the past six months.
It's only been merit lodge and tokens.
Marlo's technically a token.
>> This doesn't do much against tokens,
Wheeler.
>> No, I wouldn't. [laughter]
So, only just his fault.
>> Oh god, they're one ones and not one
one. There's so many one on one.
>> Oh my god.
>> Right. But yeah, very elegant card. It's
It feels like this is a bit too
powerful. So may I don't know. I'm
curious for this card's life cycle. Like
>> Yeah, modern players were a little
pissed about this,
>> right? If we cut this card from our
Canadian highlighter decks going forward
in the future, like we make room for
other exciting spells to come out in
2027, like I'm so curious what the next
version of this is ever going to be in
blue.
>> It's so funny. You know what I mean?
>> To just like target Ocelot Pride and
Gain 4. Like I, you know, they're just
some funny little kind of you target
like a death greeter champion and it it
hits them for
>> put this on your wii something, right?
Like Oh
>> Yes. Yeah. uh creature that that's the
it's one blue mana. I
>> I'm sold. I'm sold.
>> I haven't played blue in a long time,
but I'm sold.
>> You You should really give it a shot.
It's pretty good. [laughter]
>> Make your make your two mana MH3 of
Johnny a four five so a bolt.
>> Speaking of good blue cards.
>> Yeah. Next up, we have S uh Tyrant of
Naktamun. I tried so hard on myations.
>> You did pretty good.
>> Two mana, two-1 legendary human wizard
for one and a blue. Instant and sorcery
spells. Do you control have split-second
wheeler?
>> Yo dog, what the hell? [laughter]
>> That's a really weird line of text.
>> I mean, I feel like I'm going to likely
be in the camp that takes advantage of
this more than gets goozled by this.
>> Um,
>> it's so funny. Like, cast this
immediately. Castcape shift. Haha.
[laughter]
>> Like, thanks for the game, idiot.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, yeah. the fact that like you play
this at immediate like your opponent
doesn't actually have a chance to
respond as long as you sequence
properly, right? Like split second is a
bit of a a weird kind of effect. Uh a
weird a weird mechanic, I guess. Um it's
it's very odd. And so this is go
sequencing is going to be very
important. Like you could make this work
in like a storm deck as well, but you
have to be sure that like uh until
you like don't cast to your LED or your
Lotus until you like absolutely have to
cuz like you could be like Lotus Lotus
Pedal uh summ
into play everything from your graveyard
and and and your never pass. You guys
play Riftbound or Hearthstone cuz like
they never get a chance to do anything
if you
>> It's like Riftbound but good. Um
>> uh it's it's very funny. My condolences
to people that play CDH,
>> right?
>> Jesus. Like why did they they didn't
have to go this hard, right?
>> Uh I'll try this incape shift. I'll try
this in
Storm.
>> I'll Yeah, I'll try it in certain Storm
Shells. the probably not the like
regrowth storm, but like the fourcolor
like I'm going to always kill you on
turn four. Okay.
>> You know, like the very classic like
fourcolor no red.
>> Yeah. The other thing this does is like
if you don't go off if you don't play it
on your combo turn, you can't just like
play it as some sort of weird spellite
that's like, "Hey, I want you to spend
resources killing this creature."
>> Mhm.
>> Give me another turn.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know if it has a home outside
those two archetypes.
>> It's It's more narrow than people are
probably going to evaluate. like it is
just a When this when this card
isn't like,
>> "Oh, oh shit." When when this when this
card isn't a big problem, it doesn't
matter at all.
>> People look at split second and
sometimes overvaluate just how much
protection it gives you and you're like,
"This is like going I win button."
You're like, "Sometimes."
>> Yeah, there is there is more
counterplay. There's more stuff that you
can do.
>> You you need a re a genuine like
consideration for deck building and
sequencing. Somebody's going to play
this be like, "Okay, and then I'll
fetch." And you're like, "Oh, kill it."
Like,
>> yeah, you get priority a lot of times in
a game. Imagine you get priorities when
you go through different phases of the
game.
>> Exactly.
>> Right. Like, but yeah. All right. Next
up, we have Seasoned Cryommancer. Three
mana two human wizard for one blue
bloom. When this creature enters, draw
two cards, then discard two cards. When
you discard one or more non-land cards
this way, tap up to that many target
creatures and put a stun counter on
them. Activated ability three blue.
Exile this card from your graveyard and
draw two cards.
>> Nelly, surely this one can target two
creatures and stun both of them for
three mana. Right? [laughter]
>> Like how many times do we have to read
the card? Okay, it's possible I just
read all these cards and then got my
Shandra and my seasoned crowats are
confused. Put that in the comments. Um
[laughter]
uh yeah. No, I don't know. This seems
like another creature that we try and
scape shift. Um,
also
the Sultai decks that are looking to uh
fill their yards. So like
>> I like it. This is so weird in blue
because blue is already the color that
has the best card selection in the game.
>> Mhm.
>> And I've been really enjoying effects
like this in Boros and taxes.
>> Yeah.
>> There's like there's uh Joshua at three
and red. There's uh Tersa Lightbringer.
these like three mana cards that come
into play.
>> The regular seasoned guy.
>> Yeah. That like you know, discard two,
draw two, and give you some card
selection. In blue, it's
>> a little trickier. I mean, I'm going to
be honest, the only place I can think
about playing this in blue is in ninjas.
>> Okay.
>> Cuz like you come into play, you tap
their two creatures, it gives you an
unblockable creature to swing in with.
You can bounce it back to your hand and
create like a little bit of a of a loop
for both card selection and tempo. But I
don't know. That's that's my first
evaluation looking at the seasoned
chromancer. I I I think this card is
pretty strong. Like generically pretty
strong. Uncounterable draw that is like
not actually attached to a card is also
kind of nice, right? Like you just exile
it from your this card dies. Yeah, the
activated ability is great.
>> I was like you can counter creature like
like Esper Flash maybe likes it just
because like you get in your yard
somehow and then like surveil it into
your yard and then for five mana you
have divination. the the like the Grixus
discard mid-range decks, the the just
guy discard mid-range decks, the a blink
decks like this card as well.
>> Three animator maybe
>> three animator. Um honestly, maybe just
like a reanimator shell that isn't like
all in on trying to flip a coin to see
if they win on turn one or two,
>> right? Like the Jason Join mid-range
reanimator.
>> Yeah, Grix Rihanna mid-range.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. like this. This is just a really
good card.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh and being able to lock down
opponent's creatures. Stunning of
creatures is so strong. Yeah. It just
doesn't come up a lot in our format.
>> Is Ban Blink love of this, do you think?
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Cuz it's like you dig into your
>> I'm discarding one of my five Aison's
pilgrims.
>> You play every pilgrim. You don't need
them anymore. You can cast this.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I somehow forgot that discard existed.
It's worth noting too, this has like the
busted good new templating where like
the stun counters stack,
>> right? Like like we used to have cards
like this, like frost links where it's
like tap it and it doesn't tap next turn
and then I blink my Frostlinks and I tap
it and it still doesn't untap next turn.
Yeah.
>> Oh no, it's next turn. You're going to
untap next turn. [laughter]
>> I I I I'd be remiss if I didn't say it
cuz when I first read this I went, "Yo,
wizards, [laughter]
>> blue red wizards, baby. 2027 is the year
of blue red." Yeah, blue red wizard.
It'll happen.
>> You got that second lightning bolt.
>> Coming light wizards light and two
counter spells.
>> Dang.
>> And another manager.
>> I mean, your your flame of Anor Anor has
never been better.
>> Coming to a Friday night paper fight
near you.
>> Bono wizards.
>> Not good enough for showdown. [laughter]
>> Maybe the return of muscle wizards.
>> Nope. Un retired. Undefeated.
>> Yeah.
>> Next up, we have Theorist Proxy. This is
a two mana 03 illusion for one in a
blue. It has flash when this creature
enters empower Jace three blue and sack
this creature. The next spell you cast
this turn can't be countered. Nelly,
it's pretty weird. It should be
Wheeler's turn, but what you're you're
going to get too. Um, it's pretty weird
that you can like counter a counter
spell for three and draw a card. Like
that's kind of messed up. I guess you
could also just flash in and like block
an attacking two drop. Like this card's
got a lot of good things going on it for
like very little mana. Yeah,
>> I think
again you're probably going to consider
putting escape escape shift's kind of on
the brain, but any any it's it fits into
those like my spells can be countered
suite with Naktamoon, right, with with
Samut. Yeah. Um, but also just like I
don't know, two mana for an 03 with
flash that brings an empowered Jace
three like that even without the
sacrifice ability is a slightly exciting
rate like just a that's just a weird
card we haven't had before, right? So
like figuring out how valuable that is
is a little bit of a mind puzzle. Um,
but yeah, go ahead. What else do you
want?
>> It's got big brainstorm energy in the
sense that this has flash, but I think a
lot of the time if I have the mana, I'm
just going to be playing this on main
phase. Right. Right. Like
>> it is basically a new um
Elvis Renary.
>> Yeah, it it draws a card. It's a two
drop in blue that draws a card.
>> Uh although like if you flash it into
turn, your opponent's like, I'm going to
bolt your Jace. That feels a little bad,
but then you still have this creature
that blocks well and can set up a lethal
scape shift for Aerolingus. Uh
reanimate, you know, whatever. The fun
thing about the sacrificed ability, and
maybe this is worth saying, I don't know
if it's too much or not. You can
actually reactively sacrifice the
creature. You don't have to pro
proactively cast your spell. Wait, no,
it is the next spell. You can't you
can't target a spell on the second time
being encountered. Yes,
>> I'm sorry. I brought up a point that
literally was wrong.
>> Yeah, but that's okay. [laughter]
Um, happens all the time on
>> So, it also taps two creatures, right?
>> You've still got two more and you've
still got one more. Then we'll be even.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> I don't know why I read that. was like,
"Oh, your spell can't be countered."
Like,
>> it's okay. I've read enough comments
that are like, "I don't even play this
format. I just like hearing you guys
talk." And I took them taken them to
heart.
>> Sure. They're like, "All right, I need
to revise my point."
>> I think I think this card's really good.
I I am ex it again like they're the
timing on how you cast this card, when
you cast this card, which part of this
card you are going to uh value is
there's so much play to this card and it
just blocks. I love again I'm just dying
to tokens with Scapeshift and I really
don't want to play Pyroasm and any card
that I pyrom
>> I play Brotherhood's End uh but like any
card that I can play to make me not have
to play Pyroasm I will. And I feel like
this card
>> Yeah. draw a card,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Next up, the theorist Jace.
Bellerin Bellin Bellerin. Bellerin.
>> Bellerin. Bro, it's been like 20 years.
[laughter] Just pick one.
>> Oh, just say Jace.
>> Okay. Just say the theorist.
Jace, four mana, three loyalty Jace
static ability. At the beginning of each
opponent's draw step, you draw a card.
Plus one, create a 1-1 illusion creature
token. Minus two for each opponent.
Return up to one target artifact or
creature that player controls to its
owner's hand. And minus six, draw three.
Then put X plus one plus one counters on
each creature you control, where X is
the number of cards in your hand.
Wheeler.
>> I'm willing to be wrong, but I think
this card is probably bad. Um, it's so
like again I have scape shift on the
mind but I also have just timewalk on
the mind. Timewalk's a very powerful
card. People are now experimenting more
with timewalk in Canadian Highlander
because of its reduced points and
because of uh fantastic elasticity.
Um, and this card does not draw cards
when you are taking the extra turns.
Mhm. Um it every part of this card looks
like it would be good and then in
practice I am not enthused, right? Like
not drawing on their turn means that you
can't uh take advantage of of planes
walkers in the sense of like oh I'm
taking extra turn so I get extra
activations or whatever. Um and that
stinks. Not controlling when you draw a
card also kind of stinks. Uh getting one
ones. Okay, whatever. Uh the minus two
only returning opponent's cards is a
little like there maybe if there was
some play where like I could return my
own creature and replay it or reset a a
you know tap a Mox and activate this and
return it and replay it. You know
there's there's just not a lot of play
to this minus two. Uh especially cuz
like it's bounce bounce is always kind
of meh nowadays. Everything's got an
ETB.
>> Sure.
>> And then this ultimate.
Sure. I guess
>> seems like a weird windcon for a
planaineswalker deck in
>> Yeah. Why am I playing this man?
>> Like why am I playing this?
>> Not to be derogatory. This is very
commander coded, right? Like this seems
the sort of thing the more players you
have, the more value you get out of it.
You go a whole turn cycle.
>> You untap with it still in play, you're
ahead three cards, right? Like this is
this isn't a 1 v one planainwalker.
>> No. Yeah, it's it's definitely commander
coded. But
>> I want to point out a recent
planaineswalker that uh I we talked
about on the show. think we weren't like
I don't think anyone was super
enthusiastic about it, but I think it's
like stood up and had legs. It's is it
Maverin Fen the the or no Delian fell?
>> Professor Delenfell.
>> I do not remember that.
>> Paul, it's still it's from Stricks
Haven. It's a black and green four mana
planaineswalker that just like has a
bunch of normal looking abilities. And I
think it's it's gained some traction
there for people are trying.
>> Oh, this reminded me of um
>> it's like an Omnisler
>> of the old Omnis. It it is 2026 on
>> Yeah, it's 226 on this. But like look,
it has four abilities for four mana. But
there's the abilities are all really
short and simple.
>> Sure.
>> You know, uh four mana for black green,
five loyalty start, plus two, you gain
three life, zero, you draw a card and
you lose life just like OB. Minus three,
destroy target creature. And minus six,
you get an emblem with whenever you gain
life, target opponent loses that much
life. So it it has this thing in common
with Jace where it's like, okay, these
abilities are sort of all like okay
stuff that's happening. And then the
minus 6 kind of goes like, huh? Like, do
I need that? Like, is is that going to
win me the game? Like, will that really
work? And so, it just like doesn't seem
like to this panel, this card really
didn't seem like, oh yeah, this is
incredible. But it ended up
>> sticking around and it's fine. The thing
is, [snorts]
>> if a deck needs it, then it doesn't have
to be the best card in that deck. It's
just filling a roll.
>> But this kills creatures
>> for sure. For sure. For sure. This kills
creatures whereas Jace only bounces
them. I think possibly Blue Moon can
play this new Jace because the bounce is
going to matter more in a situation
where they maybe can't recast that
creature, right? And then the other
reason I want to say like maybe this
card will stick around because I do
agree it's commander coded and I agree
maybe it's just bad. Like I'm really not
excited about the minus 6. It's just
like actually maybe because you can just
plus one make a make a creature and draw
a card every turn in a normal game. Like
basically it says it's like the same
reason you like those theorists proxy
just now. It's like this just pumps out
pawn profits. Like every turn you get a
pawn profit. Yeah, maybe that's just
good enough even though you don't even
get to draw the card.
>> I mean it's a it's a it's a four mana
mythic planaineswalker in blue. So if
you if you manage to resolve it and like
make blockers and draw cards like I can
I can foresee a world where this hits
the table sticks around and you're like
damn this card's
>> doing a thing. I just think that there
are
>> uh you only get so many four drops in
your deck and I think that there are
similarish cards. It's worth mentioning
that yeah, pawn profit, right? Like you
make a body and you get the card draw is
kind of nice. The professor delion fell
you at you have control over when you do
a thing and what you're doing, which is
what I I like, right? If you need to
kill the thing, you get you get to kill
the thing. It's gone. If you need to
draw a card, you draw a card right then
and there.
>> It's like those that experiment with the
kids and the marshmallow or the two
marshmallows. It's like those scientists
are undervaluing how much those kids
want that marshmallow right now. Um,
>> choice matters. Yeah.
>> All right. Next up, we have Traxxos
Academy Guardian. This is a four mana
five legendary dragon construct for
three in a blue. The spell costs two
less to cast if you've cast a
non-creature spell this turn. It has
flying, it has vigilance, and it has
prowess.
I actually know. I think we're on Nelly
now.
>> I have to talk about this card. No one
else cares about it. That's totally
fine. I like this card in my style of
academy decks because if you're playing
Paradox Academy, sometimes you run into
I I should say I run into situations
where it's like I have an abundance of
storm but I don't have a win. Like you
just end up in scenarios where you can
kind of like
dirt around and you can't actually kill
your opponent because your your deck is
all just like cantrips and making mana.
but you can cast like 20 spells that
turn. Um, and so I just see this card
and I'm like, well, this is a an
artifact with flying that you can spend
only two mana on if you also cast a mana
rock and five toughness. So, I'm just
like excited to try it in decks that are
looking to delay the progress of the
opponent's aggro. And then it also has a
potential win condition if you can just
cast 19 spells, which is like a weird
thing that sometimes happens in those
decks.
>> I I do like this card. Do you
>> in very a very specific deck or style of
>> Yeah, there's only a couple spots you
ever put it.
>> It It's no And it's notable that this
card
>> could I sorry two mana artifact creature
with flying and vigilance. [laughter]
>> No, I mean go ahead.
Uh, [laughter]
it synergizes with Mox Opal.
>> It was all set up.
>> Mox Opal and Mox Amber and for what it's
worth, Mox Jasper.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> It's a legendary
>> legendary artifact dragon.
>> It's a legendary artifact dragon.
>> Uh, I I I've been trying to play Mox
Amber in artifact decks. Um, with, you
know, Oswald, Emery, Tamo, uh, Lady O,
Lady Doc, Lady Octopus, I forget her
name.
>> The mono blue one, whatever. I I picked
up a German copy and forgot what she was
called.
>> This is the kind of uh deck that, you
know, plays Mox Amber and plays Mox Opal
and you can maybe play in that. That's
also a deck that has infinite loops with
Emmery's uh and Oswalds and whatnot. So,
you know, infinitely casting a card um
is pretty good if you're triggering
prowess on a flying creature.
>> 15 is not nothing.
>> Yeah. My hesitation is that I don't
think you can play this like it's a uh
we saw a card in like M20 called like
stormwing entity that is basically this.
It's like a three mana or it's a five
mana creature three three flyer with
like prowess and when it ETBs you scry
to or whatever. Um and it cost
[clears throat]
two if you cast another spell.
>> Yeah. And so [cough] yeah, if you cast
an instant or sorcery, uh, which you
know, if you cast another legendary, an
artifact, or a dragon,
>> right? I know it's an elemental
[laughter]
>> and only has three toughness. Yeah,
>> instant or sorcery obviously a little
more restrictive than casting like
Offamoth, which which makes the the
Traxxas better, but again, we've had I
got you. I get five year six years uh
since this came out. That that was my
hesitation. But I think if you're taking
advantage of the artifact part of this
card, then
>> yeah, I just want to just talk about
Traxxos briefly. It is pretty flavor of
the week and it is extremely niche, but
I think it's cool.
>> Cool.
>> Next up, the last blue card is the way
of the cryommancer. Three mana legendary
enchantment for tuna blue. When way of
the cryommancer enters, empower Jace
five. But this also gives plains walkers
you control have minus three. When you
next cast an instant or sorcery spell
this turn, copy that spell. You may
choose new targets for that copy
wheeler.
>> So, there's this card called time walk.
It's pretty good. Um, and it shows up in
decks, [clears throat] excuse me, I'm
getting emotional, shows up in decks
that tend to play or have the ability to
play a bunch of Planaines Walkers.
>> Shocking.
>> And so, if I can tick down this stupid
token Jace and then cast Timewalk,
great. But maybe I want to draw a card
off this Jace. So, I'll take down my
Renin Six or I'll take down my Minskin
Boo or I'll take down my Tefairy three
or whatever. Um, it's funny. This is
kind of a funny card. Uh, but I I'm
willing to give it a shot. Like, I
foresee myself playing this
surveilling and then next turn I'm going
to basically kill you, right? Like,
>> yeah, you're going to take you're going
to time stretch or something. Take four
turns in a row or whatever. And it's and
the time blocks are obviously the
scariest thing, but like what if I cast
two stockups?
>> What if I cast two flow states, two
lightning bolts?
>> Two lightning bolts is probably the most
co.
>> Honestly, I'm so stoked to cast two
farseks,
right? [laughter] Like
>> I'm sold.
>> That's kind of dope.
>> Um [snorts]
>> I love that we started with the highest
possible bar of cards, time walk, and at
the end the panel's like, "Oh, too far."
It's it's worth mentioning that even as
a uh after this Jace dies, right, this
enchantment just sticks around and
you've gotten some value out of it. So,
if they deal with the enchantment, you
know, you've already got something, but
like it can just stick around and then
you later you're like, "Oh, I drew
another planaineswalker. I can play that
and then immediately minus three and
then I'm off to the races."
>> Yeah. And you can also just uh exile
this thing with your displacer kitten
and then copy your um your blink spell
to
>> Yeah. Well, do it again. going off and
getting in power J five on
>> and then you play the five mana Jace cuz
you've got infinite chase planes walkers
and you zero and you win.
>> I wasn't going to say it, but yeah.
>> All right, ready to move on to black, my
friends?
>> Yeah, let's do it.
>> All right, first up we have the blood
line recollector. This is a card that
kind of popped off when people first saw
it spoiled early on. Two mana mythic
vampire warlock 2 two. At the beginning
of each endstep, if three or more
creatures died this turn, this creature
becomes prepared. Its prepared spell is
called Ancestral Craving. It's a one
mana instant. Target player draws three
and loses three.
Go ahead. Uh, sorry. Does anybody here
want to talk about this card?
>> I don't know.
>> Like I don't even know if I can form
words. Like I'm very excited for bear
that lets me ancestral. Like best
>> best sign in blood we've ever seen. Um,
and it's on a two drop vampire warlock.
Uh, yes, please. I don't know. Like,
like, does someone have like smarter
things to say? Uh, I'm dumbfounded.
>> It has a number of downsides, obviously.
Yeah. Are you playing this in aggro? I
mean, I see three creatures dies. I'm
seeing three creatures dies. I mean,
obviously an aristocrat somewhere. Their
theirs have popped up, right?
>> That's an enter play prepared story.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's fair. We should
talk about that. Let's talk about that.
I think it's fine for aristocrats. Uh
maybe not the fourcolor variants, but
like a threecolor or a twocolor. Um it's
three creatures dying is not the easiest
thing to set up. Even in black, it it'll
happen, but like I'm not as Nelson
excited for this card, but like I could
see a world where this card hits the
table and is prepared at endstep and
it's only two mana, right?
>> Right.
>> Hell yeah. All right. Next up, we have
Dark Light Phoenix. This is a four mana
32 Phoenix for three in a black. It has
flying and haste at the beginning of
combat on your turn. If two or more
creatures died this turn, return this
card from your graveyard to the
battlefield. Try to also give this to
Nelly.
>> I mean, this is also [laughter]
>> All right, Wheeler. Go ahead, Wheeler.
>> Uh, yeah, I love Arch Light Phoenix.
It's a magic card that I've tried to
make work in this format quite a bit.
Uh, and has not I have not been too
successful. Um, this card, however, this
this is different. This is [laughter]
time.
>> I'll be I'll be um Yeah, I I could see
this maybe in uh a Ratosse deck, like
the discard deck.
>> For sure.
>> Or yeah, discard or ratose discard or
Grixus or Mardu discard. Those decks
tend to play a lot of ways of killing
creatures. Uh Aristocrats, if you can
get this into your graveyard, that's
always the hardest part. Um obviously
surveil mans, surveil lands make it a
little easier. uh to do. Um this is a
card that I'm going to do so much work
to get into play and I'm going to be
like this is this is everything I've
I've wanted and then I'm just Yeah, take
three. [laughter]
Right. Like Ark Light Phoenix is great
because uh you take like nine and then
you and they killed them all cuz you're
playing,
>> right? Yeah, exactly. like like Archite
Phoenix. This card is going to be a
bigger deal in 60 card formats where you
can actually set up the Archite thing
and there probably will be decks that do
that in I'd say standard. I don't know
about modern or Pioneer, but maybe
>> for modern for sure.
>> Modern for sure. Yeah, that's and that's
going to be fine. They sacrifice two
Drazy spawns in their green black deck
after they've loaded up their yard with
Phoenix's and attack you for 12.
>> Uh our format
>> I don't know. Yeah,
>> this is like a fine value. Honestly,
Ratos discard.
>> I might try it in dredge, too.
>> Like dredge or aristocrats, like
something where I can I'm going to have
things die and I'm going to put a bunch
of stuff in the yard.
>> I do love this card, but I also agree
with with Wheeler 100% here. It's like
you have to jump through a big hoop just
to like attack them for three. Um, which
I think is a lot less than jump through
big hoop to draw three cards. I'm more
excited to do that. Yeah.
>> Uh, next up, Dark Matter Manipulator.
This is a one mana one-two human warlock
for a single black pip. When this
creature enters mill three, this card
gets plus two plus O for every seven
cards in your graveyard. Nelly. Okay,
this one's weird because it is like a
potential in monol black aggro. Um
I I doubt it, but may I'd be interested
to be proven wrong that the Sultai like
delve cards delve decks want to play it.
I don't think they want to. Does this
does this work with like a mopplasm
kill? Like one of these
>> old Yeah, there's probably some There's
And [laughter] then that actually
excites me about it. There's some combo
potential for this card.
>> I'm just playing this on turn one and
turn two. I'm tapping bizarre back.
[laughter]
>> Yeah, sure. Stuff it in your dredge
decks. But also, if you just want to
like I don't know what the easiest
shortest path to just putting your whole
library in your B, it's probably that
druid, right? Like you can just play
this turn two player hermit druid and
then [laughter] turn three just try to
protect the queen and make it
unblockable and hit them for lethal,
right? Like what is what is sorry two
>> times your deck divided by seven? It
doesn't it can't even get to 20, can it?
>> This cricket gets for every seven in
your graveyard. So you're going to have
like about I I would say you will have
about 80. I I I think it's reasonable
for this to for your deck to have about
84 cards in it. I cast Pure Through the
Abyss a lot, which is draw half your
library, right? And uh by half by by
half your library, what they mean is uh
41 to 43 cards every single time.
>> So, you mill 82 cards, you've you've
used up 18 cards setting up your opening
hand and your cards and play and stuff,
right?
>> And like you've mil 84, that's around
12.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I don't think
>> for 17 one shot them. It doesn't even
[laughter] one shot.
>> Doesn't one shot them, but it is only
one mana.
>> I don't know.
>> Cool. All right.
>> Wait, wait, wait.
>> You got to give a double strike, too.
>> What?
>> I I'm just trying to work out all of
your mana one shot. No, no, no, no, no.
>> It gets plus two. Yeah, you're wrong.
You're very wrong. Wrong. Gets plus two
plus zero for every seven cards.
>> Right. You have 70 in your graveyard.
>> Oh, that's everyone. Yeah.
>> Right. [laughter] Yes. So if you have
84, which is I never said I could do
>> 12* 2. Yeah, I know. I noticed
[laughter]
>> it can one time. I'm telling you it can
>> loading ready run. We need to have a pro
D day where we just focus on basic
arithmetic.
>> We do grade five level math.
>> Begging the the manage Paul, you're on a
black. What is 2 + two? And we're just
sweating. This is Kiki cheeky cradle
hoof all over the god.
>> It's a weird thing that magic players do
where they're like start the calculation
right and then at some point you're like
no
>> well they make a mistake in the middle
but they don't catch it. Yeah. And like
what I did mentally was I divided by two
a second time for some reason. Anyways
yeah you can you can give it plus 20
power.
>> You give it plus 20 power.
>> Yes you can. Yeah.
>> Can we move on just to move away from my
shame?
>> Yeah sure. Why not?
>> Don't be ashamed. Never be ashamed of
your common mistakes. Yeah. Yeah. I
misread uh the spell on theorist proxy.
I got basic wrong, but Lich's relic will
sur will save me. One man equipment.
When this equipment enters, you may pay
two when you do for each opponent.
Destroy up to one target creature or
planaineswalker. That player controls.
Equipped creature gets plus two plus
one. Equipped for two wheeler.
>> Uh yeah, I'm very excited to play this
card in pixie.
>> I was going to say this is this is so
pixie coded.
>> This is extremely pixie coded. Uh, Mardu
or Esper. Um, or fourcolor.
>> God, the pixie thing that lets you
destroy a target creature.
>> Yeah, target creature. We got Cruel. We
got Cruel Bent Blade from uh Hobbit,
which is just an edict and three mana.
Um, the fact that you could cheat this
into play, pay two, and blow up a thing
is pretty nice. Uh, plus two plus one
ain't nothing. Like, you throw that on a
Glint, they're going to die very
quickly. I think you could maybe even
experiment with this card in uh Orzov
decks that run stone forge and cloud. I
was going to say honestly stone forge
being able we've been getting such an
incredible list of toolkit enchantments
equipment pardon me
>> for all the stone forge stuff like
chainsaw sort of started it off and now
we've gotten the near
>> we've come a long way from uh phantom
blade from Assassin's Creed which was
like a five mana uh equipment in black
then when it etbed it killed a creature
and they were trying that one in legacy
so like now that it's one mana and you
can kill a planes walker and like it's I
mean it's one mana to play obviously two
to activate
>> with the stone forge being able to use
it off the activated ability too cuz you
can you can put it into play
uncounterable and then pay the
additional mana that's
>> wow that's really strong
>> I mean it's worse than phantom blade if
you're putting it in with stone forge
but other than that every other time
it's good it's better yeah
>> no I like this card a lot
>> it's one mana
>> or three mana
>> all right next up sinister mastermind is
a three mana five5 legendary Human rogue
with threshold. You can't cast this
spell unless there are seven or more
cards in your graveyard. It has menace
and an activated ability. Black and
discard this card. Target creature gets
- 3 - 1 until end of turn. You're both
tapping your fingers. Are you racing to
see who gets it? We're just being like
pro. We're just doing the art.
>> That's fair. Uh Nelly, this is a weird
one. I've I want to do the check of Do
you want to play this in dredge?
>> Uh no.
>> No, that's totally fine. So the upside
here is three mana 55 five menace.
That's that's good. That you know if we
could just cast this on turn one that's
a good clock. Like it's [laughter] not
it's not quite Reggie but it's got
menace.
>> Oh you just want to like ritual this
turn one?
>> Sure. I mean
>> that's some terrible news for all of
you.
>> Oh you can't cast a spell unless there
are seven more cards in your graveyard.
Is that the terrible news?
>> That's the terrible
>> Yeah. Yeah. For sure. No, I I wanted to
say like that's that's the next thing to
talk about is like, you know, you have
to be in the middle of the game to cast
this. Uh if you draw it early, obviously
you can bolt the bird and
>> maybe that's good enough and we should
shouldn't overthink it. You should try
it out in your decks that are caning
like your your Grix mid-range, whatever.
>> I casting this.
>> You're not casting. Just want to discard
it.
>> Discarding it. Casting on Earth.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Or I'm like, you know, I'm casting on
Earth or helping hand or
>> Yeah, I think that's fine. I respect
that. And maybe we'll see some longevity
here with that pattern. I just wonder
that there aren't going to be an
abundance of creatures that don't demand
that you play the removal side first and
then the only way you can put it in is
with one of your unears. Like it seems
like it's a it's a tough bar, but this
is a cool card. There's a really
interesting play pattern that Ratosse
can take advantage to see a lot of games
which is turn one cycling oifant or the
troll of Kazadun to set up an early
reanimate and being able to get another
like five power creature on turn two in
that deck that's like so easy to enable
is kind of cool.
>> Five five menace.
>> Yeah, I think I think this card is going
to kill some people at Yellow Jacket
comics and
>> specifically. Okay, great.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, the final black card we have
is Vasa's Final Mercy. This is a two-
mana sorcery for black. Black. Choose
one. You lose two life, destroy target
creature or planaineswalker. Or you lose
two life. Empower Jace six
wheeler.
>> So it's two mana. You lose two life,
destroy target creature planaines
walker. Right. [laughter]
>> Like I very
>> sometime we've already had the best sign
of blood ever, but you have to kill
three creatures on your turn to prepare
it. So now we've got the second best
sign of blood ever.
>> This is not my type of card. I've move,
but it's uh the I just
>> lose two, draw two over the course of
two turns
>> just feels a little rough. Like I I
guess you could surveil and you kind of,
you know, you get a little bit of um
>> so there's a little texture in how you
use this, but I look at this card and I
go, "Oh, cool. Infernal Grasp that can
hit my opponent's planaines walkers at
sorcery speed for an extra for double
black or whatever." Like it's just
>> that's most of it.
>> Yeah. I I wouldn't overthink this card.
I imagine it's mostly just killing your
opponent's cards for two mana.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, that's mostly what it's doing,
>> right?
>> I didn't announce this at the top, but
good news everybody, you get a fourth
color today. We're going on to red as
well, and we're going to start with a
Johnny's Anguish X and a red for an
enchantment. When this enchantment
enters, it deals X to any target.
Creatures you control have trample.
[laughter]
I saw, knock them butt ahead, I saw the
funniest line of text where they're
like, [laughter]
>> I don't want to call them out if this
post went viral, but they're like, "Wow,
this card solves all the issues with
Tarmago." [laughter]
>> I was just like, "Is your issue with
Goif doesn't have trample?" Like, it's
the classic like Have you seen that meme
of like, "Buddy, we have been talking
about this. You're just 21 years old."
Whatever. Like it's like yeah we no it's
we've accepted this we
>> you know what go really needed was a
fireball
>> well we got there
>> solved all the go problems killed my
opponent with [laughter] fire
>> Serge there is goif with fireball it's
called pyrogoy
>> that's true
>> anyways Nelly what do you think of
>> yeah sincerely though I like this card
for a few reasons um it's rare that we
get a fireball that we talk about on
this show uh because the power level of
doing fireball in general is lower than
you want by quite a bit for Canadian
Highlander, but giving your creatures
trample in the current format is very
relevant. Um, a lot of the creatures
>> finally goifact.
Well, it's Baroggo that comes to mind
when I think of this card and it's an
enchantment that's also a removal spell
and those have been often favored by
it's, you know,
>> like to bring it back like it is mostly
goify,
but like we also acknowledge that it was
goif
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah. You still play it even
though it's not perfect.
>> Yeah. The fact that this is pushing you
to play a different card type that makes
go bigger.
>> Show a 2010 magic player a card from
this set.
>> This is a custom card.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This is the You would have
seen this on MTG Salvation.
>> Sorry. What? Fireball. But it's an
enchantment. Like Yeah, bro.
>> Yeah, dude. [laughter]
Yeah. It's so good against my Ragavan's
revenge or whatever, right? Like
>> uh it's I will I'd consider this in
Mardu Pixie. It's kind of cool. Oh,
yeah. [laughter] Oh, I didn't even think
about it for Party Pixie. No, but you
know what else I was thinking about it
is you could play it in red prowess
decks as well.
>> You know what I mean? It's kind of cool
and
>> Can you imagine if like 2015 Hoof had
access to this card,
>> right?
>> I mean,
>> maybe.
>> Right. Like a good old classic red green
hoof.
>> As far as like cards to play next to
Gaia's cradle that aren't creatures,
this is kind of
>> Fireball does kill people.
>> Yeah. Yeah, you can still kill people.
>> They die if you go upstairs. this card.
It's funny. [laughter] It's very funny,
but it's not, you know, it's not
nothing.
>> It's not Fourth Heirlingus. Don't Don't
get it twisted. It's not Fourth
Heirling.
>> It's not a blue. This isn't a blue card.
It
>> It just [laughter] Yeah, it just, you
know, it might show up. I don't know. I
think it's I think it's neat.
>> I do, too.
>> Yeah. All right. Next up. Oh, this
card's exciting. Crater Claw Colossus.
This got spoiled a while ago as well.
Seven mana, five five artifact creature
beast construct for four red red.
>> It has eight.
>> Why is it seven?
>> What do you mean seven?
>> It's only seven. It's weird. Sorry, keep
going.
>> No, no, no. Sorry, you're misreading
this. It's two in a blue. [laughter]
>> When this creature enters, creatures you
control, gain trample and get plus X
plus O until end of turn, where X is the
number of artifacts you control.
[laughter]
>> Wheeler.
>> Oh, I I'm going to kill people with
this. Oh [snorts] yeah, they gave red
hoof for artifact
>> first. They printed again. This is blue.
This is not red. Uh I mean it it is red
if I have Goblin Welder in play.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh we got Cyberdrive Awakening.
>> Are you worried about seven? Cuz Hoof is
eight.
>> Well, Hoof and then the Moonshaker
cavalry were both eight, right? There
was three of the colored pips and five.
So, for some reason in the the card the
card type that nullifies uh the generic
costs of things anyway, even if you
aren't casting Tinker, they just made it
one less to begin with.
>> Yeah, this card feels like it should be
eight mana because you're still just
killing your opponents, right?
>> Yeah. Anyways, it doesn't matter.
>> The the point being uh I'm going to put
this into play with Tinker or Goblin
Welder and uh I'm hopefully just going
to kill my opponents.
>> This is going to kill so many people so
quickly. Yeah, we got Cyberdrive
Awakener. That uh was a wet fart. Uh
there was the one from Edge of
Eternity's Deep Shaker Titan or
whatever, and that was an even wetter
fart.
>> Uh and then this card might be a little
bit of a wet fart, but I think this is
closer to like, no, you'll just kill
people. You'll make enough servos or
thopters,
>> treasure tokens, like how many attackers
do you want? Is two good? Like
>> the funny Yeah. The funny thing about
this
>> eight artifacts in play.
>> Yes, exactly. is that like you don't
have to go as wide. You just need like
>> one cornstruct and this.
>> Yeah. And it'll get Yeah. Plus
bajillion. Plus a bajillion.
>> Um Yeah, dog. It it they're going to
die.
>> I played in the decks that put it into
play.
>> Watch out. This is This exists now. What
if Iron Giant Yeah. Like what if Blit
Steel just already had haste? You didn't
need a second card to go with it.
>> Mhm.
>> Next up, we have the curse marred demon.
four mana four four demon for two red
red flying and trample and when this
creature enters search your library for
a card put it into your hand and then
discard a card at random Nelly
>> oh yeah uh so
>> you want you want to gamble you feeling
like a gambling man
>> I'm in gambling I'm in okay so um not a
card that is going to show up in a lot
of decks um but an interesting card to
just be aware of I myself personally am
very interested and I know I'm not the
only one in the community on demons that
cast demonic tutor when they enter the
battlefield. And this is only four mana
instead of like seven or eight and it
cast gamble instead of demonic tutor.
And so I just think that on its own, you
know, brewers go and have fun. This
isn't the card that you need to be
worried about across the table that
they're going to windmill slam. You're
going to lose to you're more likely to
lose to it if you put it in your own
deck because you're [laughter] trying
something cool and fun and you know
that's a lot of why you came to Canadian
home.
>> Okay.
>> So be aware this card exists. So, this
card is kind of funny.
>> Yeah,
>> cuz you find Fire Blast
>> and you just if you got, you know, you
play this out, you got one other card in
your hand, you find the fire blast and
you flip the coin and if heads domes
them for four immediately or if you have
uh no other cards in hand and five mana,
it finds fiery temper and deals three to
something.
>> Yeah,
>> I think this card's bad, but it could
kill you. Like,
>> we haven't talked about medium red in a
long time. Is this a medium red card off
of ancient? mana. No, it's it's
definitely like a weird, right?
>> No, it's a weird combo applications
card. Like you either want to be like
stuffing your graveyard with the Intomb
half of Gamble or you want to just
legitimately be like trying to combo and
you're just like I'm just going to cast
Gamble and hope my hand is better.
>> It's fire blast dog. You just find your
fire blast. Find the fire blast and kill
them. Or or detectives Phoenix is not
>> sure. I was going to say like maybe
Mardu discard maybe like if you don't
care about what you're discarding.
>> Gamble is a terrible card unless you're
finding Black Lotus. Sure.
>> That's or underworld breach or whatever.
Yeah.
>> Well, okay. Watch out. Coming to, you
know, demons and storms near you on the
horizon.
>> Yeah. You'll see this card against is it
wizards [laughter] on Friday night.
>> Yes. Yes. Uh, next up we have Marwin the
Clear Cutter. One mana, two-1 legendary
elf warrior for single red pip. Two in a
tap. Sack an artifact or land draw a
card. Nelly. Okay, it's yet another
Savannah Lions with upside. this ability
two and a tap sacrifice an artifact or
land. Um we've seen on some like draft
coded cards already that admittedly we
liked in draft. I'm not sure how great
it's going to be in constructed, but now
is our time to find out because they
slammed it on to weirdly a red elf that
has two power. So, I just think in your
most aggressive versions of Red Deck
wins, you can try it out. And maybe the
additional utility you get from drawing
into more burn spells after this thing
can't attack anymore is is where you're
going to go. I I don't think this is
like a definitely long-term card either,
but cool flavor of the week for Red
Liquids. Next up, we have Master of
Barbs. Two mana, two-1 Lizard Bard for
two in a red. has menace. Whenever one
or more opponents are dealt non-combat
damage, creatures you control get plus
one plus O until end of turn. Like a
weird prowess.
>> I thought he said master of barbs.
Sorry, I thought you said lizard barb.
Like it's [laughter] like like this is
Barb. She is the master of all the
barbs.
>> I mean, this card is just going to be
Barbara, right? For sure.
>> Barbara
Barb's pissed. [laughter]
>> Look how mad Barb is. Someone did not
return.
>> Barb wants to talk to your manager.
Manis is doing a lot of heavy lifting uh
here. It's I I don't hate this card. I
like actually I'd go so so far as to say
I like this card um mostly in the like
spells slinger version of red. I feel
like red has a couple of different
versions now. Um and it's all about how
a player feels like they can beat a
baroggo.
>> Sure. And the the benefit of the spell
slinging version is that they can get
away with playing some cards like
scorching shot uh or the uh roast even,
right? Like to deal with
>> big damage big yeah the big damage
spells to get rid of the shields and the
barog and what metamorphosis fanatics
and whatnot. Um because they also it
comes with a ping or it comes with a
prowess trigger and being able to uh
like spread some damage across to
creatures that don't have the best body
like a Kessig flame breather is kind of
appealing. Um and then yeah just menace
is so broken like one toughness ain't
ain't great but does um do the red deck
still play hired claw?
>> Yes. Like doesn't hired claw have sort
of an interesting synergy with this as
well because it's not specifically a
spell. It's like non-combat damage.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah. Non. That's what I'm
getting at with the like the pingers,
the flame breather and whatnot is that
you can push really push damage. The the
combo with this and hired claw is that
uh if my opponent plays one of them and
then plays the other, I'm dead.
[laughter]
>> That's the A plus B. Hired claw um is
still getting some play in our format,
but outside of that, I think possibly
for more time even, we're going to see
the now I've forgotten the name of it,
but it's a generic, a red, and a white
creatures you control get plus one.
>> War leaders call. Thank you. So, barb
next to the war leaders call and the
token strategy is also pretty exciting.
Yeah, I I I lost A to Boro's tokens
recently and they had Agot Instigator
which is a two mana one three uh that is
an Impact Tremors but it also has uh
Offspring and that's that's a card that
in the in the token stack.
>> Yeah, someone asking if people are
actually still playing Impact Tremors
too, but I know they play this one.
>> War is very strong. I've even thought
about it in Boros. It's a little bit
slow for like the DNT style. Like you
really want a
>> W. Impact Tremors is like not worth it,
but the second you add anything on top,
it's like, "Oh, this is one of the best
cards to draw in like turn three or turn
four."
>> Right. Right. Right. From the commander
product. Thank you, Paul.
>> Yeah. So, there
>> we've seen this in cube a bunch.
>> There are ways to take advantage of the
fact that Master Barbs cares about you
having a big board and pushing
non-combat damage. But I also just like
that it makes some of the creatures that
push non-combat damage that have kind of
a disappointing stat line like it puts
them into a position where they're a
genuine threat.
>> Right.
>> All right. Next up we have the pompous
battle mage. One mana 1-1 goblin
sorcerer for a single red has prowess
and it enters prepared and that it has a
prepared spell called improvised act.
It's a sorcery. You may discard a card
if you do draw a card.
Yep. Great. We wanted more swift
spirits.
>> Yeah. No haste, but like this will hit
you for two to three every turn. And it
it just has this spell.
>> Yeah.
>> This is so funny.
>> It's like a little better than the ammon
cat one that infects your creatures or
whatever, right? Like this is probably
our second best. Or is there a mouse
that's got also a one mana prowess? I
don't know. The one mana prowess cannon
is going to include pompus battle mage
for quite a while, I think.
>> Yeah, cuz it's so funny how simple it
is. Yeah, it's going to be a regular
though.
>> Yeah,
>> doesn't need more words on it.
>> No, that's the thing.
>> Next up, we have Summit Hazeret's
Champion. Two mana, two two legendary
creature, human warrior, cleric.
>> Creatures you control have haste. I'll
throw an Ellie here.
>> I used to run like this, but now I run
like this. It's way faster.
>> Um, actually though, uh, Sammit getting
two cards with like two mana and two
power and one line of text. That's kind
of awesome.
>> Yeah. like um so the first of these
cards was concordant crossroads, but
that gave all of your opponents
creatures haste as well.
>> World enchantment.
>> Yeah, enchant world from legends, but
it's the first card in Magic that was
just like everything has haste. Have
fun. Um and since then, we've usually
had to pay I want to say three mana.
Fervor and Ferver and there's a creature
as well that the ones I've been enjoying
are just like the three drops that have
like more power and toughness and then
they just give a thing haste when it
enters the battlefield or like the four
mana red green um the the lovers in the
forest from Innistrad. I like that one a
lot. But this is a two drop.
>> Oh, the lesbians.
>> The lesbians. Yeah. Yeah. What? Sorry.
You're like lovers in the forest and
industry. I'm like grog and th
[laughter]
>> I mean
>> yeah um I don't know what else to say
tell you about this. It's two for two
who two that I'm going to lose to
someone on Boros humans with this card
>> like next to Barb also it's particularly
terrifying or in in tokens I think it's
also kind of scary. There's just a lot
of places you can put
>> two for two. It's not even hard.
>> Two two for haste is genuinely
terrifying.
>> Yeah. Two or [laughter]
>> two mana two with haste
>> is genuinely terrifying.
>> Like two two for haste, right?
>> Like if I'm against a Grul opponent and
they play RipClan Crasher, which is just
a two mana 2 two haste.
>> Uh that is infinitely more scary to me
if I'm on combo than like any number of
card that they have convinced themselves
is for the combo matchup, right? Like
it's just like oh god. Like just don't
play Goblin War buggy on the turn I need
you not to, you know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This thing will deal at
least four damage and will contribute to
dealing more,
>> right? Like this card into like Miglaws
and all of a sudden I'm at like nine on
turn three.
>> This into like three fairy or the the
third Thalia, sorry.
>> I mean those are the three fairies also.
>> That's also pretty good.
>> I meant I meant a three mana Thalia.
>> Oh yeah. I'm never blocking. I'm always
dying. Great.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. And finally, the last card of
the day is the Sting Caster Mage. two
mana 2 one human wizard for one in a red
with haste. When this creature enters
target instant or sorcery card in your
graveyard gains flashback until ending a
turn flashback is equals its mana cost.
Wheeler take us home. So this is one of
the first cards that got previewed for
this set uh and also got leaked actually
but uh my evaluation of this card has
changed. I cast a lot of sorcery speed
snap cer mages.
>> Um snapcaster gets a lot of strength
from having flash and having the
flexibility of you know obviously
holding up your mana and whatnot and
counter spells. So, that's not nothing.
But like, snap caster cast a uh a serum
visions or whatever. Fine. Snapcaster
cast lightning bolt to get rid of the
creature or flame slash. Great. Uh
duress, thoughts, like you can name any
number of really powerful one mana or
two mana, instant and sorceries, uh that
will have a a very reasonable impact on
the board or the game or just like cash
in and leave you a body. Um, and that's
great. Like [laughter] I I initially was
like, "Oh, I flash back lightning bolt
or chain lightning or like monstrous
rage, sorcery speed, cuz it just doesn't
matter. They're dead."
>> It will sometimes.
>> And it will do that. It will do that.
This card has, remember what we said
about uh Simote being uh
>> uh two mana, four haste, whatever I
said. Yeah, this this also does that.
>> Um where it's just a two power haste
creature on two if you really need it.
Uh but if you uh wait a turn uh you get
to flash back a card and kill a creature
or push more damage. And like I'll
probably try this out in some versions
of Scape Shift. Like I've been on
Songcrafter Mage.
>> Oh, which has some strength and it made
me realize like I just want as many
Snapcasters as I can get. Doesn't matter
if it's sorcery speed. I will cast this
and flash back a farsek or a time and
have a blocker.
>> Just give me a road bump on a regrowth.
>> Yeah, basically.
>> Yeah. And it's another one of those for
sure. Yeah.
>> Or on your on your time walk turns like
it attacks for two that turn. Sometimes
that matters as well.
>> And like I just like a a ratos player
going like turn one hand attack, turn
two blood tight harvester, turn three
this hand attack. I'm like, "Oh yeah,
I'm I'm dead."
>> Yeah.
>> All right, friends. That is going to do
it for part one of our Reality Fracture
set review. If you think we missed any
cards, if you want to continue the
discussion on any of the cards we hit
today, hit us up in the comments down
below. I've been Serge and joined by the
wonderful Nelly
>> reality
>> Wheeler
>> Refraction. Thank you to Paul for
running tech.
>> Hello. A reminder that everything you do
is brought to you by you, your support
of the Patreon over at
patreon.com/loading
readyun. Don't go too far cuz next up
we're going to bring part two of the set
review. So we'll see you then. [music]
Thank you so much for watching. Until
next time, goodbye.
>> [music]